Spence, Bill and Andy; Papers apap400
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Bill and Andy Spence Papers
1960-2022
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap400
22.19 cubic ft.
This collection contains materials related to the lives of Bill and Andy Spence, including folk and traditional music and materials documenting the Fox Hollow and Old Songs Festivals.
Content Description
The Bill and Andy Spence Papers are divided into five series: 1.) Fox Hollow, 2.) Subject Files, 3.) Pickin' and Singin' Gatherin', 4.) Old Songs Administration and 5.) Old Songs Activities. The records were originally compiled by Andy, with handwritten notes explaining the couples' relation to and the significance of organizations like Fox Hollow and the Hudson River Sloop. The collection includes flyers, newsletters, news clippings, publications, conference records, financial statements, meeting minutes, pamphlets, advertisements, correspondence, photographs, and audiovisual materials.
The bulk of the Fox Hollow materials are from Andy Spence's scrapbook on the folk festival as well as LPs. The Subject Files series deals heavily with the Spences' association with the North American Folk Music and Dance Alliance, the Hudson River Sloop "Clearwater," and arts in the New York Capital Region, as well as the musicals created and directed by Andy. Newspaper clippings saved by Andy relating to folk musicians and events are available in this series. Some folk albums and CDs retained by Andy also are part of Subject Files. Pickin' and Singin' Gatherin' is a smaller series consisting of newsletters and information on the folk music organization's events. The Old Songs Inc. materials comprise the bulk of the collection, given its founding by Bill and Andy in 1977 and Andy's executive role with the organization and the Board of Directors. The organization's administrative records include correspondence between Andy and her fellow Board members, finances, meeting minutes, emails, and reports. The Old Songs Activities series contains a large portion of information on the Old Songs Festival, including paper records, CDs, and photographs of the festival, as well as flyers from the wide variety of general events that Old Songs staged. Oversize posters from the Fox Hollow Festival and Old Songs productions are notable in the series. Maps and site plans for the Dutch barn on the Altamont Fairgrounds sponsored by Old Songs may also be of interest to researchers.
Biographical Note
Born in Iowa, spouses Bill (1940-2019) and Kay "Andy" Spence relocated to Voorheesville, N.Y. in 1965. For decades, the two were involved with folk and traditional music in the Capital Region. In 1966, Bill and Andy joined other area folk music lovers to form an organization that would promote the singing and playing of folk music at home, which became Pickin' and Singin' Gatherin' (PSG). The first newsletter was released in May of 1967. That same year, Bill and Andy Spence attended the Fox Hollow Festival in Petersburgh, N.Y. where PSG members served as volunteers. PSG helped Bob Beers, the festival's founder, clear land and build areas for the performances and activities. The Fox Hollow Festival was a weekend full of events bringing together folk artists and folk music fans to enjoy performances and vendors. In May 1972, Bob Beers died in a car accident, and, by September 1973, Andy Spence had resigned from her position on the Board of Directors for the Fox Hollow Festival.
Fox Hollow inspired Bill and Andy Spence to establish the nonprofit Old Songs, Inc. in 1977 to present folk and traditional music and dance to the public through concerts, performances, and group instruction. The first Old Songs Festival was held in 1981 in Guilderland, N.Y. before moving to the Altamont Fairgrounds the following year. Andy served as director of the festival until 2017. The festival, held each June, is the largest event conducted by the organization, drawing in thousands of folk music devotees annually for a weekend of camping, workshops, and listening to and performing folk music. In 1994, Andy was at the forefront of Old Songs' sponsorship of the construction of an 18th century style Dutch barn on the Altamont Fairgrounds to become the Center for Traditional Arts and Agriculture.
Andy Spence served as executive director of Old Songs, Inc. until 2018 when she became executive director emeritus. In 1998, Bill Spence retired from the University of New York at Albany where he worked as a specialist in television, audio, and graphic design. The two also formed Andy's Front Hall, a full-service mail-order business for selected folk music recordings, books, instruments, and accessories which they operated for decades. Bill was a musician for more than 60 years. He played banjo, guitar, and Autoharp but was best known for playing the hammered dulcimer. In 1970 he formed a string band named Fennig's All-Star String Band with musicians living in the Albany area brought together by PSG. Bill also produced some LPs. From 2008 to 2017, Andy actively created and directed local musicals, with Bill starring as one of the performers.
Bill and Andy Spence were also involved in the launching of the Hudson River Sloop "Clearwater." In 1969 and 1970, Bill served on the Board of Directors for the Hudson River Sloop Restoration Inc., and even conceived the name "Clearwater."
Bill and Andy Spence had one daughter, Hannah, a graduate of Oberlin Conservatory of Music, Oberlin, Ohio.
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Don Person donated 164 reel-to-reel tapes in October 2020. Andy Spence donated materials in August 2021, May 2022, and November 2022.
Arrangement of the collection
The collection is arranged into five series - 1.) Fox Hollow, 2.) Subject Files, 3.) Pickin' and Singin' Gatherin', 4.) Old Songs Administration and 5.) Old Songs Activities. With the exception of Subject Files, all are arranged chronologically. Sugject Files is arranged alphabeticcally.
Spence, Kay "Andy"; Spence, Bill (Musician); Folk music festivals; Old Songs, Incorporated; Music; Mail-order sound recording industry; Folk music-United States; New York (State); Photographs; Clippings.; Newsletters.; Administrative records.; compact discs
- Fox Hollow Festival, 1966-2021; 5.93 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  Scope and Contents
  Folk music aficionados Bill and Andy Spence retained photographs, newspaper clippings, posters, schedules, flyers, and audio of the Fox Hollow Festival, of which they were involved in through their Capital District folk organization, Pick'n' and Sing'n' Gather'n' (PSG). The Beers family (Robert, Evelyne, and Martha) of Petersburgh, N.Y. held the Fox Hollow Festival on their family farm celebrating the traditions of folk music and arts every year from 1966 to 1980. The Festival consisted of multiple days packed with folk singing groups, workshops, art showings, activities, entertainment, dancing, games, speakers, crafts, and special guests with camping and other site accommodations upon request. This festival served as inspiration for the Old Songs Festival created in 1981 by Andy. The passing of Robert Beers in May 1972 signaled a shift for the Fox Hollow Festival, and Bill and Andy's last year of participation was 1973. PSG were involved as volunteers with the festival from 1966 to 1973, and Andy resigned from the Fox Hollow Board of Directors in September of that same year.
  This series includes Andy's scrapbook pages (the bulk of the series' contents), LPs and CDs, and black and white photographs taken by Dick Levine at the festival from 1966 to 1971. LPs of recordings from some of the festivals are included.
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Petersburgh, N.Y., Photographs by Dick Levine, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Fox Hollow Photographs by Dick Levine, 1966 (Oversize 1, Folder 3)
  - The Archive of Fox Hollow Festival by Kay "Andy" Spence (1 of 2), 1966-2021; Undated (Oversize 1, Folder 1)
  - The Archive of Fox Hollow Festival by Kay "Andy" Spence (2 of 2), 1966-2021; Undated (Oversize 1, Folder 2)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1967 August (Reel 30_01)
  - 1967 Fox Hollow Festival, "Pitter, Poon, the Rain Come Doon" - Vol. I (Lp 1)
  - 1967 Fox Hollow Festival, "Clitter, Clatter, Down Come the Water" - Vol. II (Lp 2)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Petersburgh, N.Y., Photographs by Dick Levine, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Fox Hollow Photographs by Dick Levine, 1967 (Oversize 1, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1967-1972; Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1968 August (Reel 28_01b)
  - "All Those People…," Fox Hollow 1968 - Vol. III (Lp 3)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1968 (Reel 123_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1968 (Reel 128_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1968 (Reel 129_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1968 (Reel 130_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Petersburgh, N.Y., Photographs by Dick Levine, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Fox Hollow Photographs by Dick Levine, 1968 (Oversize 1, Folder 5)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1969 February (Reel 27_02)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1969 August (Reel 27_01)
  - "…And Not One Police," Fox Hollow 1969 - Vol. IV (Lp 4)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Petersburgh, N.Y., Photographs by Dick Levine, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Fox Hollow Photographs by Dick Levine, 1969 (Oversize 1, Folder 6)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1970 August (Reel 22_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1970 August (Reel 108_02)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1970 August (Reel 109_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1970 August (Reel 132_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1970 August (Reel 133_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1970 August (Reel 147_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Petersburgh, N.Y., Photographs by Dick Levine, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Fox Hollow Photographs by Dick Levine, 1970 (Oversize 1, Folder 7)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1971 August (Reel 13)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1971 August (Reel 14)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1971 August (Reel 15_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1971 August (Reel 16_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1971 August (Reel 19_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1971 August (Reel 87)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1971 August (Reel 88_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1971 August (Reel 89)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1971 August (Reel 90)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1971 August (Reel 91)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1971 August (Reel 92)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1971 August (Reel 93)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1971 August (Reel 94)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1971 August (Reel 131_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1971 August (Reel 134_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1971 August (Reel 135_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1971 August (Reel 139_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1971 August (Reel 145_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1971 August (Reel 146_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Petersburgh, N.Y., Photographs by Dick Levine, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Fox Hollow Photographs by Dick Levine, 1971 (Oversize 1, Folder 8)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1972 August (Reel 1)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1972 August (Reel 2)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1972 August (Reel 3)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1972 August (Reel 4)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1972 August (Reel 5)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1972 August (Reel 6)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1972 August (Reel 7)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1972 August (Reel 8)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1972 August (Reel 9)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1972 August (Reel 10)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1972 August (Reel 11)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1972 August (Reel 12)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1972 August (Reel 17_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1972 August (Reel 18)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1972 August (Reel 20)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1972 August (Reel 21_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1972 August (Reel 23_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1972 August (Reel 26_01)
  - Fox Hollow 1972 - Vol. VII (Lp 5)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1973 August (Reel 45)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1973 August (Reel 46)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1973 August (Reel 59)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1973 August (Reel 60)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1973 August (Reel 61)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1973 August (Reel 62)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1973 August (Reel 63)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1973 August (Reel 65)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1973 August (Reel 66)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1973 August (Reel 67)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1973 August (Reel 68)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1973 August (Reel 69)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1973 August (Reel 70)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1973 August (Reel 71)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1973 August (Reel 72)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1973 August (Reel 73)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1973 August (Reel 74)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1973 August (Reel 113_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1973 August (Reel 140_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1973 August (Reel 158)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1973 August (Reel 159)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1973 October (Reel 52_01)
  - Festival Planning, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1973 (Reel 114_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1973-1974 (Reel 50_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1974 January (Reel 105)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1974 February (Reel 48)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1974 February (Reel 75)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1974 August (Reel 40)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1974 August (Reel 41)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1974 August (Reel 42)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1974 August (Reel 43)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1974 August (Reel 44)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1974 August (Reel 47)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1974 August (Reel 51_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1974 August (Reel 53)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1974 August (Reel 54)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1974 August (Reel 55)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1974 August (Reel 56)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1974 August (Reel 57)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1974 August (Reel 58)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1974 August (Reel 99_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1974 August (Reel 100)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1974 August (Reel 155_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1974 August (Reel 156_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1974 August (Reel 157)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1975 August (Reel 24_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1975 August (Reel 76)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1975 August (Reel 77)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1975 August (Reel 78)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1975 August (Reel 79)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1975 August (Reel 80)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1975 August (Reel 81)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1975 August (Reel 82)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1975 August (Reel 83)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1975 August (Reel 84)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1975 August (Reel 85)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1975 August (Reel 95)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1975 August (Reel 96)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1975 August (Reel 97)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1975 August (Reel 98)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1975 August (Reel 101)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1975 August (Reel 102)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1975 August (Reel 103)
  - 10th Anniversary Album, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1976 July (Reel 119_01)
  - Fox Hollow Lodge String Band Festival - Vol. I, "Comin' Home", 1976 (Lp 6)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1978 June (Reel 39)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1979 February (Reel 106_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, 1982 April (Reel 117_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival Collection Report by Field Horne, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Fox Hollow Reunion Concert Pin, 1994 October 15 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Fox Hollow Photographs by Dick Levine, Identification by Andy Spence, 2021 April (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 25_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 28_01a)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 31_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 31_02)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 32_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 33)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 34)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 35)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 36)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 37)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 38)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 49)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 64)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 86)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 104)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 107_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 108_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 110_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 111_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 112_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 115_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 116_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 118_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 120_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 121_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 122_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 124_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 125_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 126_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 127_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 136_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 137_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival (no audio), Undated (Reel 138_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 141_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 142_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 143_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 144_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 148_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 149_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 150_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 151_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 152_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 153_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 154_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 160)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 161)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 162_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 163_01)
  - Fox Hollow Festival, Undated (Reel 164_01)
  - "The Portable Folk Festival" Poster, Undated (Oversize 2, Folder 1)
  - Recordings of the Fox Hollow Folk Festival, Undated (Cd 1)
    Original Recording 1979
  - Recordings of the Fox Hollow Folk Festival, Undated (Cd 2)
  - Recordings of the Fox Hollow Folk Festival, Undated (Cd 3)
  - Recordings of the Fox Hollow Folk Festival, Undated (Cd 4)
  - Recordings of the Fox Hollow Folk Festival, Undated (Cd 5)
- Subject Files, 1960-2022; 2; 3.45 cubic ft.
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  The Subject Files of the Bill and Andy Spence Papers contain records of folk events, organizations, and conferences that the couple were involved with; calendars; newspaper clippings; photographs; literature; and more related to folk music and the arts. Publications from Andy's Front Hall Records, Andy Spence's folk music storefront, are included in the series. Individual files on figures involved in the folk music scene such as Don McLean, Pete Seeger, and Capital District folk music cafe-owner Lena Spencer were compiled and retained by Andy. Records of the musicals created and directed by Andy and starring Bill have their own files in this series. Files on both the North American Folk Music and Dance Alliance and Folk Alliance Conference comprise a significant portion of this series. Records and photographs related to Bill and Andy's personal interests such as the launching of the Hudson River Sloop "Clearwater" are also included. A variety of LPs and CDs are also available in the series.
  - Andy Spence Calendar, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Andy Spence Date Log, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Andy Front Hall Records (1 of 3), 1978-2004; Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Andy Front Hall Records (2 of 3), 1978-2004; Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Andy Front Hall Records (3 of 3), 1978-2004; Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Arlo Guthrie, 1968; 1970; Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "The Art of the Psaltery," Robert H. Beers, Undated (Cd 6)
  - Articles by Walter Koenig Reviewer, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Barefoot Boy with Boots On," John McCutcheon, 1981 (Lp 7)
  - "Bright Shining Morning," Lou and Sally Killen, 1975 (Lp 8)
  - "Bygone Days: Music for Dulcimer and Hurdy-Gurdy," Roger Nicholson and Jake Walton, 1980 (Lp 9)
  - Caffe Lena (1 of 2), 1960-2021 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Caffe Lena (2 of 2), 1960-2021 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Calendar, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Christmas with the Beers Family, Featuring: The Three Little Drummers", Undated (Lp 10)
  - Clearwater, The Hudson River Sloop, 1970; Undated (Flat-file 1)
  - Clippings, Arts in the Area, 1980-2020; Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, Don McLean, 1970-1972; Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Clippings, Folk Music, 1981-2010; Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Clippings, Pete Seeger, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Clippings, Sailing, 2009; Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Collector's Series, Bob White, 1977 (Lp 11)
  - "Contrasts," Rick and Loraine Lee, 1978 (Lp 12)
  - "Dance, Like A Wave Of The Sea," Walt Michael and Tom McCreesh, 1978 (Lp 13)
  - The Dildine Family, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "The Dildine Family", 1974 (Lp 14)
  - Don McLean Feature, Life Magazine, 1972 January 14 (Oversize 3, Folder 1)
  - "Dookin for Apples," Alistair Anderson with Fenning's All-Star String Band, 1979 (Lp 15)
  - "Down with the Rent" The Anti-Rent Rebellion in New York, 2008; 2014-2017; 2021-2022; Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "Down with the Rent! The Anti-Rent Rebellion of New York State," November 21, 2015 (Cd 7)
  - "Dumbarton's Drums," the Beers Family, Undated (Lp 16)
  - Eighth Step, 1973-2020; Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "An Evening at the English Music Hall", 1984 (Lp 17)
  - "Fennigmania," Fennig's All-Star String Band, 1981 (Lp 18)
  - "Fiddler Beers Sings Psalty Psongs with Psaltery and Pfiddle," Bob Beers, Undated (Lp 19)
  - "The Flip Side of my Fiddle," Bob Beers, Undated (Lp 20)
  - Folk Alliance Conference, Boston, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Folk Alliance Conference, Chicago, Official Program, 1991 January 24-1991 January 27 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Folk Alliance Conference, Portland, Oregon, 1995 February 16-1995 February 19 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Folk Alliance Conference, Toronto, February 12-16, 1997, 1996 February 15-1996 February 18 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Folk Alliance Conference, Washington D.C., 1996 February 15-1996 February 18 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - "Forward Into the Light," Directed by Andy Spence, 2015; 2017-2018; Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Forward Into Light: Sand Lake Center for the Arts," November 2017 (Cd 8)
  - "Four Seasons, Four Years - The Civil War: A Musical Journey", 2012 (Cd 9)
  - "Four Seasons, Four Years - The Civil War: A Musical Journey," Directed by Andy Spence, 2012-2013 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Fourgone Conclusions: Contra Dance Music from Western Massachusetts", 1983 (Lp 21)
  - "The Gentle Art," Evelyne Beers, Undated (Lp 22)
  - "The Gentleness in Living," Eric and Martha Nagler with Evelyne Beers, 1973 (Lp 23)
  - "The Golden Skein," Featuring Bob and Evelyne Beers, 1972 (Lp 24)
  - "The Good Old Way," Walt Michael and Company, 1985 (Lp 25)
  - "The Hammered Dulcimer," Bill Spence with Fennig's All-Star Band, 1973 (Lp 26)
  - "The Hammered Dulcimer Strikes Again," Bill Spence with Fennig's All-Star Band, 1977 (Lp 27)
  - "The Host of the Air," Michael, McCreesh, and Campbell, 1980 (Lp 28)
  - "The Hudson River: Pete Seeger's Voyage to Save It," Look Magazine, 1969 August 26 (Oversize 3, Folder 2)
  - Hudson River Sloop, Clearwater (1 of 2), 1968-1972; 2022 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Hudson River Sloop, Clearwater (2 of 2), 1968-1972; 2022 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Hudson River Sloop, Clearwater, Photographs, 1969 May 17 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "Introducing the Beers Family", Undated (Lp 29)
  - Jackie Alper Obituary, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "Kissing is a Crime," Debby Saperstone and George Wilson, 1979 (Lp 30)
  - "Land of My Youth: American Piping in the Scottish Tradition" Mark Cushing and Don Lindsay, 1983 (Lp 31)
  - "Live at Holstein's! Eat Bertha's Mussels," John Roberts and Tony Barrand, 1983 (Lp 32)
  - "Make the Wildwoods Ring," Gary, Margaret, Megan and Dan MacArthur, 1982 (Lp 33)